

#### CONTACT

Address
Grillenberg 1
3160 Traisen
Austria

**Phone number** +43 68184013023

Email lisa.hollaus@live.at

GitHub https://github.com/LisaHollaus

# **SKILLS**

### **Technical:**

- Python: OOP, Databases, Networking, Django, Concurrency
- R: Statistics, Visualization
- Web: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, JavaScript
- Networking: Cisco Packet Tracer, Wireshark
- Databases: SQLite, SQLAlchemy, neo4j

#### **Analytical:**

- Data Analysis
- Project Management
- Organizational Skills

## Soft:

- Adaptability
- Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- Cultural Awareness

# **Hollaus Lisa-Maria**

# Informatics Student

#### **PROFILE**

As a passionate student currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in informatics (with a focus on Data Science at IMC University of Applied Science), my background includes not only technical skills and various work experiences, but also a unique 1.5-year period of traveling across Europe, Northern and Central America between 2021 and 2023, enriching my adaptability and broadening my global perspective.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelancer

10/2022 - Present

upwork.com

Remote, small jobs

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01f41de3c5d1e4ff81?mp\_source=share

#### Agricultural worker

09/2020 - 09/2023

(inconsistently)

Restaurant ('Most-Buschenschank') and organic farm Hollaus Traisen, Austria

www.grillenberg.at

- Seasonal work
- Production of home-grown juice, sirup, jam, liqueur, schnaps,...
- Food and beverages service

#### Farm hand

11/2021 - 12/2021

workaway.info

Hegranes, Iceland

- Animal care
- Basic household chores

#### Office Assistant

03/2021 - 05/2021

District Chamber of Farmers Lilienfeld, Austria

- InfoPoint
- Assistance with Funding applications
- Transferring data; digitization

#### Confectioner (including apprenticeship)

09/2016 - 09/2020

**Bakery Florian Hink** 

Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

Employed in all fields including:

- Basic Austrian sweets production
- Baking and decorating cakes for special events
- Pralines manufacture
- Seasonal work like Christmas cookies and Ice-cream production

#### **Practical:**

- Agriculture & Food Production
- Animal Care
- Childcare & Home Care

## **LANGUAGES**

German (Mother tongue) English (Level C1 – main language at university) Spanish (Beginner)

#### **HOBBIES**

- Hiking
- Cooking and Baking
- Travelling
- Reading
- Learning new skills

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

Home care aid

Volkshilfe Traisen & Nursing home Türnitz

Austria

Kindergarten Assistant

Kindergarten Kirchengasse

Traisen, Austria

**Service** 07/2015 – 08/2015

Confectionary Felbermayer Lilienfeld, Austria

**EDUCATION AND TRAINING** 

UNIVERSITY 2023 – Present

Informatics bachelor's degree program (3. Semester)

IMC University of Applied Science

Krems an der Donau, Austria

Computer Science focused on Data Science

**'BERUFSREIFEPRÜFUNG'** 09/2017 – 02/2021

(A-Level - general qualification for university entrance)

Berufsförderungsinstitut (BFI)

St.Pölten, Austria

https://www.bfinoe.at/

**Evening-classes** 

APPRENTICESHIP 2016 – 2018

Confectioner

**Bakery Florian Hink** 

Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

TECHNICAL SCHOOL (3 years)

Skilled worker for agriculture- and household-management

Fachschule Sooß

Sooß, Austria

Graduating with "Mittlere Reife" (GCSE), as well as:

- ECDL (European Computer Driving License)
- HACCP certificate
- Allergy-training-course
- Kindergarten assistant
- Home-helper
- Medical office assistant with diploma course
- Baby Fit (Babysitter)

#### TRAVEL EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2023

2013 - 2016

05/2016 - 07/2016

11/2015

- 14 months long solo travel across northern Europe, Iceland, Northern and Central America
- Engaged in cultural exchanges and intercultural work experiences through 'Workaway'
- 4.5 months long solo walk (pilgrimage) from Austria to Spain in 2023